Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Manuscripts, correspondence and other materials by and about George Cruikshank, circa 1811-1976, 234930; (30 boxes)
  - Sub-Series A: Borowitz collection, circa 1792-1891, 235269
    - Sub-sub-series 4: Sketches and drawings, notes, fragments, printed material, 1819-1878, undated, 235270
      - Buttonhole of a naughty boy caught by a nail, 235292 (Box 87, Folder 16)
      - Dorset Street, Salisbury Square, Fleet Street, 235291 (Box 87, Folder 17)
      - Fencing, 235290 (Box 87, Folder 18)
      - George drawing on his mantelpiece and William Hone and George Cruikshank seated at table, 235289 (Box 87, Folder 19)
      - Lady's head dressed overnight, 235288 (Box 87, Folder 20)
      - Linkmen putting out lights, 235287 (Box 87, Folder 21)
      - Napoleon Bonaparte and King's carriage, George running by the side of it, 235286 (Box 87, Folder 22)
      - Portrait of a gentleman and Street lamp lighting - old and new, 235285 (Box 87, Folder 23)
      - Prepared for an attack and Capture by Bow Street officers disguised as women, 235284 (Box 87, Folder 24)
      - Republican Beaux, 2 prints, 235283 (Box 87, Folder 25)
      - Superstition, 235282 (Box 87, Folder 26)
      - A theory of our world, flat world, 235281 (Box 87, Folder 27)
      - A theory of our world, hollow earth, 235280 (Box 87, Folder 28)
      - Time sweeping away all things and Sedan chair and linkmen, 235279 (Box 87, Folder 29)
      - Tinderbox, 235278 (Box 87, Folder 30)
      - Ventilated hat, or a Martello Tower, 235277 (Box 87, Folder 31)
      - Ventilation and A theory of our world, railway engine, 235276 (Box 87, Folder 32)
      - Worshipping and Clerkenwell pump, 235275 (Box 87, Folder 33)
      - Pencil, pen and ink drawings, undated, 235274 (Box 87, Folder 34)
      - The Period, with a caricature and article on George cruikshank, 1870, September 17, 235273 (Box 87, Folder 35)
      - Notes, fragments, sketches, other manuscript material, circa 1850-1869, 235272 (Box 87)
      - Bound volume, William Bates, George Cruikshank, The Artist, the Humourist; and the Man, 1878, 235271
  - Sub-Series B: Frank S. Bradburn, circa 1811-1974, 235204
    - This series contains notes, transcriptions of letters, illustrations and other printed material relating to the research and collection of Frank S. Bradburn, 235268
    - Sub-sub-series 1: Research and catalog notes, correspondence, other printed material, 1824-1974, 235218
      - A.M. Cohn, book plates and photograph, undated, 235267 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - A.M. Cohn, short story, undated, 235266 (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - A.M. Cohn, Cruikshank caricature index (2 folders), 235265 (Box 88, Folder 3-4)
      - Advertisements, 1878, undated, 235264 (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - The Artist and the Author, notes, correspondence, clippings relating to this 1872 pamphlet, 1951-1962, 235263 (Box 88, Folder 6-7)
      - Bradburn - bookseller correspondence, 1944-1957, undated, 235262 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Bradburn - correspondence, notes, 1931-1955, undated, 235261 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Bradburn - correspondence, primarily with J.C. Trewin and Ronald Searle, 1960 July 29 - 1962 March 23, undated, 235260 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Bradburn - correspondence with J.C. Trewin and Ronald Searle, 1962 August 12 - 1963 November 25, undated, 235259 (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Bradburn collection catalog, 1st draft, circa 1950, 235258 (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Bruce statue, notes, 235257 (Box 88, Folder 13)
      - Catalogs and catalog slips, circa 1942, 235256 (Box 88, Folder 14)
      - Charles Dickens exhibition, 1970, 235255 (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Clippings, George Cruikshank death notice, 1878, 235254 (Box 88, Folder 16)
      - Clippings, Emma Catherine Cruikshank, 1878 February 28, 235253 (Box 88, Folder 17)
      - Clippings, 1948-1974, 235252 (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - Clippings, bound volume (catalog slips), undated, 235251 (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, autographs, (W. Hone and H. Brown, "Phiz"?), 1824, 1840, 235250 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence (and copies), 1842-1910, undated, 235249 (Box 88, Folder 21)
      - Descriptions of works and catalogs, 235248 (Box 88, Folder 22)
      - George Cruikshank and George Mills, 235247 (Box 88, Folder 23)
      - George Cruikshank and the public, 235246 (Box 88, Folder 24)
      - George Cruikshank and temperance, 235245 (Box 88, Folder 25)
      - George Cruikshank and W.H. Merle, 235244 (Box 88, Folder 26)
      - George Cruikshank as a painter, 235243 (Box 88, Folder 27)
      - George Cruikshank as a Volunteer, 235242 (Box 88, Folder 28)
      - George Cruikshank as illustrator, 235241 (Box 88, Folder 29)
      - George Cruikshank at work, 235240 (Box 88, Folder 30)
      - George Cruikshank family affairs, 235239 (Box 88, Folder 31)
      - George Cruikshank in finance and commerce, 235238 (Box 88, Folder 32-33)
      - George Cruikshank, manuscript material for Tower of London, accounts, draft of What Will You Drink, circa 1840-1878, 235237 (Box 88, Folder 34)
      - George Cruikshank sales catalogs [1870-1880], notes and photocopies, circa 1972, 235236 (Box 88, Folder 35)
      - George Cruikshank, testimonials, 235235 (Box 88, Folder 36)
      - George Cruikshank, will (photocopy), 1878 April 16, 235234
      - London Exhibition, 1974, 235233 (Box 88, Folder 38)
      - Mrs. George Cruikshank, 235232 (Box 88, Folder 39)
      - Notes, bibliographical material on 19th century fiction, undated, 235231
      - Notes, bibliography of Cruikshank works, index of separate prints, undated, 235230 (Box 88)
      - Notes, Cruikshank biographical and family data, 235229 (Box 88, Folder 42)
      - Notes by George Cruikshank, other data, 235228 (Box 88, Folder 43)
      - Notes, lists, 1955, undated, 235227 (Box 88, Folder 44-47)
      - Notes, receipts, 1943, 1951, 1953, undated, 235226 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Notes, miscellaneous, fragments, undated, 235225 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Notes, rough draft, Doubtful 19th century editions, undated, 235224 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Personal information and list of Cruikshank acquaintances ,undated, 235223 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Photocopies, Cruikshank articles, undated, 235222 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Photocopies, Cruikshank correspondence, illustrations and other printed material, circa 1842-1878, 235221 (Box 89, Folder 6-7)
      - Photocopies and facsimiles, Charles Dickens, 235220 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Rubbings, Cruikshank and Dickens covers, undated, 235219 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Sub-sub-series 2: Illustrations, 1811 - 1913, 235205
      - Bibby's Annual, 1913, 235217 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Calendars, black and white lithograph specimens, 1882, 235216 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Colored lithograph specimens (chromolithographs), circa 19th century, 235215 (Box 90, Folder 3-9)
      - George Cruikshank's house, undated, 235214 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - Illustration, La Boilly, undated, 235213 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Illustrations for Sketches by Boz, [ 1836], 235212 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Illustrations, including A Theatrical Exit, Lazare, and etchings by Robert Cruikshank, circa 1800's, 235211 (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Illustrations, various, including Monsier Mallet, by Robert Cruikshank, advertisements, and wrappers, circa 1800's, 235210 (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - Music, lyric sheets, undated, 235209 (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Portraits of George Cruikshank, 1811-1878, undated, 235208 (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Scraps and Sketches, 1828, 235207 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Steel plate for Tower of London, [1840], 235206 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series C: Christopher C. Kohler, circa 1823-1876, 235137
    - Series is arranged by Kohler catalog number. An index to these numbers can be found in box 50, folder 1 and a copy of the catalog with descriptive information is located in box 39, folder 12. This collection contains correspondence, envelopes, drafts of letters (unsigned), sketches, prescriptions, printer's bills, cards, advertisements, and drafts of articles., 235203
    - Kohler I: Sketches, envelopes, prescriptions, advertisements, cards, printers bills, letters and draft letters from George Cruikshank to Mrs. Cruikshank and "anon" (unknown correspondents), circa 1823 - 1876, 235202
    - Sketches, undated, Kohler 204, 214, 235201 (Box 91, Folder 1-2)
    - Envelopes, addressed to Mrs. George Cruikshank, George Cruikshank and Mrs. L. Jones, 1851-1860, Kohler 65, 205, 225, 226, 235200 (Box 91, Folder 3-6)
    - Prescriptions and prescription envelopes, circa 1859-1876, Kohler 222-224, 227-229, 235199 (Box 91, Folder 7-12)
    - Advertisements, calling cards, printer's bills, circa 1860, Kohler 193, 3, 203, 219, 201, 235198 (Box 91, Folder 13-17)
    - Letters and draft letters from George Cruikshank, 1823-1876, Kohler 67, 6, 12-13, 16, 37, 32, 40-46, 50, 55, 69, 58, 63-64, 68, 47, 91, 94, 151-152, 167, 184, 187, 154, 196-197, 210, 218, 236, 235197 (Box 91, Folder 18-50)
    - Kohler II: Draft letters, correspondence and notes from and to George Cruikshank, circa 1837-1876, 235196
    - Draft letters from George Cruikshank to persons A-T, 1837-1873, Kohler 27-28, 30, 35, 25, 36, 105, 34, 51-52, 66, 96, 9, 48, 75, 149, 21, 39, 46, 8, 60-62, 49, 71, 59, 19, 20, 72-73, 87, 100, 235195 (Box 92, Folder 1-39)
    - Letters and notes to George Cruikshank, 1869, 1876, undated, Kohler 89, 38, 209, 221, 212, 235194 (Box 92)
    - Kohler III: Manuscript material on a number of subjects including the Bruce statue, Cruikshank works such as The Betting Book, Ass on the Ladder, advice on cholera, and temperance topics. Also includes notes and contracts, circa 1840-1872, 235193
    - Advice about the cholera, undated, Kohler 88, 235192 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - All Round My Hat, 1851, Kohler 74, 235191 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Ass on the Ladder, 1840, Kohler 85, 235190 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Autobiography, drafts and notes on recollections and persons by George Cruikshank, undated, Kohler 53, 262-269, 235189 (Box 93, Folder 4-12)
    - Drafts of "Bands in the Park on Sunday," [1855], Kohler 192, 235188 (Box 93)
    - Draft of a speech on betting, notes, sketch, undated, Kohler 230, 235187 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Manuscript material on "The Betting Book," 1852, Kohler 232-235, 237, 235186 (Box 93, Folder 17-21)
    - Draft letter, 1863, Kohler 231, 235185 (Box 93, Folder 22)
    - The Bruce statue, 1872, Kohler 97-99, 235184 (Box 93, Folder 23-30)
    - Copy of a letter which his Grace the Archbishop of Canterbury ought to have written to the Right Hon. Lord Viscount Palmerston M.P. upon the subject of the Military Bands Playing in the Parks on Sundays, draft versions, 1855, Kohler 192, 235183 (Box 93, Folder 31-32)
    - Temperance Rifle Corp., circa 1863-1868, Kohler 146-150, 235182 (Box 93)
    - Draft entitled, The Criminal Punishments of the Chinese, undated, Kohler 1, 235181 (Box 93, Folder 38)
    - Drafts of an article commenting on the "Review of the Exhibition of the Royal Academy and other art galleries," by John Stewart, undated, Kohler 31, 235180 (Box 93, Folder 39)
    - Crystal Palace and Gin Palaces, copy of parts of the Prospectus of the Crystal Palace, 1852, Kohler 29, 235179 (Box 93, Folder 40)
    - Drafts concerning "Beer Shops and Public Houses" springing up in the vicinity of the Crystal Palace, undated, Kohler 155, 235178 (Box 93, Folder 41)
    - Draft of a memo of agreement between Cruikshank and Joseph Hogarth, concerning the engraving and printing of "The Culprit Detected," undated, Kohler 17, 235177 (Box 93, Folder 42)
    - Material relating to drunkenness and the Sabbath, circa 1855, Kohler 15, 235176 (Box 93, Folder 43-50)
    - Kohler IV: Manuscripts, Equality to Glass, circa 1851-1872, 235175
    - Drafts of articles on equality, undated, Kohler 90, 189, 235174 (Box 94, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts of articles on etiquette, undated, Kohler 79-81, 235173 (Box 94, Folder 3-5)
    - Drafts of articles, title pages and text regarding The Fairy Library, circa 1851-1854, 235172 (Box 94, Folder 6-8)
    - Drafts and notes, including a sketch, "Fishing with a frying pan, or Grid Iron," 1872, Kohler 92, 235171 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Papers relating to "A Discovery Concerning Ghosts," 1863, Kohler 261, 235170 (Box 94, Folder 10-12)
    - Notes, drafts for the pamphlet, "The Glass and the New Crystal Palace," 1855, Kohler 106-145, 235169 (Box 94, Folder 13-52)
    - Kohler IV: Manuscripts, Guy Fawkes to Supernatural, circa 1829-1875, 235168
    - Draft part of a note on the drawing of "Guy Fawkes treated classically," 1844, Kohler 95, 235167 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Note on William Hone, [1835], Kohler 56, 235166 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Drafts relating to "The House that Jack Built," circa 1854, Kohler 180-181, 195, 235165 (Box 95, Folder 3-5)
    - Articles on Roman Catholicism, [1869], Kohler 76-77, 235164 (Box 95, Folder 6-7)
    - Rough pencil drafts on "John Bull and the Atmospheric Dining Room," with sketch, undated, Kohler 248, 235163 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Lists of names, days and appointments, figures and other Cruikshank ephemera, undated, Kohler 206-207, 208, 213, 211, 215-217, 202, 220, 235162 (Box 95, Folder 9-18)
    - Draft of an article on Mungo Park, 1875, Kohler 93, 235161 (Box 95, Folder 19)
    - Copies of parts of two plays, undated, Kohler 238, 235160 (Box 95, Folder 20-23)
    - Papers relating to, "A Pop-Gun Fired off by George Cruikshank in defense of the British Volunteers of 1803, against the uncivil attack upon that body by General W. Napier," 1860, Kohler 249-260, 235159 (Box 95, Folder 24-35)
    - Draft on prefaces, undated, Kohler 194, 235158 (Box 95, Folder 36)
    - Programs, one for a musical program, the other for a ceremony at which Cruikshank is to lay he first brick of a building, [1867], undated, Kohler 2, 33, 235157 (Box 95, Folder 37-38)
    - Drafts of an attack on Pusey, Newman and the Oxford Movement, undated, Kohler 78, 235156 (Box 95, Folder 39)
    - Pencil drafts with a sketch of people dining, undated, Kohler 247, 235155 (Box 95, Folder 40)
    - Papers relating to "Remarks on Education; with a Slice of Bread and Butter on the same subject," circa 1870, Kohler 242, 239, 235154 (Box 95, Folder 41-42)
    - Selection of Cruikshank signatures, undated, Kohler 198-200, 235153 (Box 95, Folder 43-45)
    - Draft of a satire entitled, "The Slanderer," [1829], Kohler 54, 235152 (Box 95, Folder 46)
    - Drafts for "A Slice of Bread and Butter," circa 1870, Kohler 240-241, 243, 235151 (Box 95, Folder 47-49)
    - Draft of an address to the Manchester Athenaeum, undated, Kohler 18, 235150 (Box 95, Folder 50)
    - Drafts of an article on the prevention of house-breaking, "Stop Thief," undated, Kohler 84, 235149 (Box 95, Folder 51-57)
    - One page of a story, possibly a fair copy, beginning, "so, at last in Paris and I'll be bound I'm the greatest rip in it…," undated, Kohler 246, 235148 (Box 95, Folder 58)
    - Drafts of an "Effusion to the Papers," concerning Harriet Beecher Stowe's erroneous remarks on Cruikshank; also mentions The Fairy Library, [1854], Kohler 57, 235147 (Box 95, Folder 59)
    - Sheet with the heading, "Sunday," and numbered 13, "if you by accident should go to church…," undated, Kohler 82, 235146 (Box 95, Folder 60)
    - Drafts concerning the supernatural and Cruikshank's belief in the existence of the soul, undated, Kohler 14, 235145 (Box 95, Folder 61)
    - Kohler VI: Manuscripts, Teeth - Worship of Bacchus, circa 1837-1873, 235144
    - Advice about the front teeth, circa 1853, Kohler 70, 235143 (Box 96)
    - Note about Professor Wheatstone and the laying down of a submarine telegraphic line in the Bay of Swansea in 1837, undated, Kohler 191, 235142 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Papers, speeches and notes relating to the temperance movement, circa 1848-1853, Kohler 103-104, 170-175, 156-158, 160-166, 176-179, 244-245, 185-186, 101, 235141 (Box 96, Folder 7-49)
    - Draft on the unhealthy nature of draughts, etc..., 1873, Kohler 86, 235140 (Box 96, Folder 50)
    - Drafts and articles, "What will you take to drink?," circa 1848-1850, Kohler 22-24, 235139 (Box 96)
    - Papers relating to the painting, "The Worship of Bacchus," 1869, undated, Kohler 4-5, 7, 10-11, 235138 (Box 96, Folder 61-65)
  - Sub-Series D: Ronald Searle, circa 1826-1892, 235055
    - Arranged by Searle number, this series contains sketches, draft letters, correspondence, bills, envelopes, lists, and other manuscript material. Subjects covered in this series include the Bruce statue, various works such as The Betting Book, Fairy Library, Ingoldsby Legends, and others. Manuscript material on temperance topics, the Volunteers and the Worship of Bacchus is included. A cross-reference to this collection is located in box 54, folder 1. Detailed descriptions of each item can be found on notecards in box 106. Much of the correspondence includes transcriptions of the letters in each folder, 235136
    - Searle I: Sketches and manuscripts, drawing and watercolors, circa 1834-1877, 235135
    - Sketches, sketchbooks, manuscripts, drawings and watercolors, circa 1834-1875, Searle 1a - 49a, 235134 (Box 97, Folder 1-49)
    - Letters from George Cruikshank, A-T, 1841-1877, undated, Searle 1-20, 235133 (Box 97, Folder 50-69)
    - Draft letters from George Cruikshank, recipients unknown, circa 1847-1877, Searle 22-70, 235132 (Box 97, Folder 70-120)
    - Searle II: Draft letters by George Cruikshank to recipients A-Y, circa 1841-1877, 235131
    - Draft letters from Cruikshank to recipients unknown, circa 1841-1873, Searle 71-117, 235130 (Box 98)
    - Draft letters from George Cruikshank and letters to Cruikshank, A-T, circa 1850-1877, Searle 118-181, 235129 (Box 98, Folder 46-109)
    - Draft letters from George Cruikshank and letters to Cruikshank, T-Y, circa 1857-1872, Searle 182-200, 235128 (Box 99, Folder 1-19)
    - Manuscript material on the following subjects, persons and publications:, 235127
    - Searle III: Manuscripts: Art to Temperance, circa 1839-1876, 235126
    - "What is Art?," undated, Searle 201, 235125 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Baldwyn trust, undated, Searle 202-203, 235124 (Box 100, Folder 2-3)
    - Note regarding monetary agreement with Bentley, undated, Searle 204, 235123 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - "The Betting Book," undated, Searle 205-210, 235122 (Box 100, Folder 5-10)
    - Bills, 1866, Searle 211, 235121 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - The Bruce statue, undated, Searle 212-216, 235120 (Box 100, Folder 12-16)
    - Buriel grounds, undated, Searle 217, 235119 (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - Cheque fragment, 1872, Searle 218, 235118 (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - Children, undated, Searle 219, 235117 (Box 100, Folder 19)
    - Critics, 1872, 235116 (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - "Discovery Concerning Ghosts," undated, Searle 221-232, 235115 (Box 100, Folder 21-32)
    - Drama, undated, Searle, 233-234, 235114 (Box 100)
    - Education, undated, Searle 235-238, 235113 (Box 100)
    - Etiquette, undated, Searle 239, 235112 (Box 100, Folder 39)
    - Extraordinary circumstances, undated, Searle 240, 235111 (Box 100, Folder 40)
    - Fairy Library, Puss in Boots, [1864], Searle, 241, 235110 (Box 100, Folder 41)
    - Financial papers, 1839-1874, Searle 242-251, 235109 (Box 100, Folder 42-51)
    - "F. Oconner's Armless Speech in Cockney Land," undated, Searle 252, 235108 (Box 100, Folder 52)
    - Fools, undated, Searle 253, 235107 (Box 100, Folder 53)
    - Glass and the New Crystal Palace, [1853], Searle 254-257, 235106 (Box 100, Folder 54-57)
    - Housing, undated, Searle 258-259, 235105 (Folder 58-59)
    - Human nature, undated, Searle 260-261, 235104 (Box 100, Folder 60-61)
    - Illustration, undated, Searle 262-267, 235103 (Box 100, Folder 62-67)
    - Ingoldsby Legends, [1847], Searle 268, 235102 (Box 100, Folder 68)
    - Irish, undated, Searle 269, 235101 (Box 100, Folder 69)
    - "Lawyer," undated, Searle 270, 235100 (Box 100, Folder 70)
    - Money, undated, Searle 271-272, 235099 (Box 100, Folder 71-72)
    - "Mother's Love," undated, Searle 273, 235098 (Box 100, Folder 73)
    - Names and addresses, letters, 1856, 1861, 1870, undated, Searle 274-280, 235097 (Box 100, Folder 74-80)
    - Newspapers and editors, undated, Searle 281, 235096 (Box 100, Folder 81)
    - Our Gutter Children,[1869], Searle 282-284, 235095 (Box 100, Folder 82-84)
    - Periodicals, undated, Searle 285, 235094 (Box 100, Folder 85)
    - "A Pop-gun Fired Off," [1860], Searle 286-287, 235093 (Box 100, Folder 86-87)
    - Postcard addressed to Cruikshank, 1876, Searle 288, 235092 (Box 100, Folder 88)
    - Preface and culture, undated, Searle 289-290, 235091 (Box 100, Folder 89-90)
    - Religion, undated, Searle 291-299, 235090 (Folder 91-99)
    - "The Rules of the Road," undated, Searl 300, 235089 (Box 100, Folder 100)
    - Scrawls, sketches, undated, Searle 301, 235088 (Box 100, Folder 101)
    - "The Sky Lark," undated, Searle 302, 235087 (Box 100, Folder 102)
    - "A Slice of Bread and Butter," [1857], Searle 303, 235086 (Box 100, Folder 103)
    - Society, undated, Searle 304, 235085 (Box 100, Folder 104)
    - Taxation, undated, Searle 305, 235084 (Box 100, Folder 105)
    - Teeth, undated, Searle 306, 235083 (Box 100, Folder 106)
    - Temperence, circa 1856-1876, 235082 (Box 100)
    - Searle IV: Manuscripts: Theatre to Young Caretaker and letters to George Cruikshank from persons anonymous to C, circa 1826-1878, 235081
    - Theater, "All the World's a Stage," undated, Searle 329, 235080 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - History of the term, "Tippy Bob," 1876 August 15, Searle 330, 235079 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - "Tower of London," [1840], Searle 331, 235078 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Ventilation, 1873 January 24, undated, Searle 332-334, 235077 (Box 101, Folder 4-6)
    - Volunteers, 1868, undated, Searle 335-346, 235076 (Box 101, Folder 7-18)
    - "Worship of Bacchus," 1871, Searle 347-356, 235075 (Box 101, Folder 19-28)
    - "Young caretaker," undated, Searle 357, 235074 (Box 101, Folder 29)
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, sender unknown, 1844, 1848, 1850, undated, Searle 358-365, 235073 (Box 101, Folder 30-37)
    - Letter to George Cruikshank from Charles Kent, January 9, 1851, Searle 366, 235072 (Box 101, Folder 38)
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, sender unknown, 1851-1878, Searle 367-380, 235071 (Box 101, Folder 39-52)
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, A-C, 1826-1878, Searle 381-455, 235070 (Box 101)
    - Searle V: Letters to George Cruikshank from persons D-J, 1847-1877, 235069
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, D-J, 1847-1877, Searle 456-525, 235068 (Box 102, Folder 1-70)
    - Searle VI: Letters to George Cruikshank from persons K-N, 1839-1877, 235067
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, K-N, 1839-1877, Searle 526-587, 235066 (Box 103, Folder 1-62)
    - Searle VII: Letters to George Cruikshank from persons O-T, 1827-1878, 235065
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, O-T, 1827-1878, Searle 588-657, 235064 (Box 104, Folder 1-70)
    - Letters to and from George Cruikshank, letters referring to Cruikshank, letters to Mrs. Cruikshank, printed materials, 1848-1892, 235063
    - Letters to George Cruikshank, W, 1848-1877, Searle 658-677, 235062 (Box 105, Folder 1-20)
    - Letter from George Cruikshank to Vizetelly & Branston (engravers), 1829 July 15, Searle 678, 235061 (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - Letters referring to George Cruikshank, 1853-1892, Searle 679-684, 235060 (Box 105, Folder 22-27)
    - List of subscriptions to the George Cruikshank testimonial, 1875, Searle 685, 235059 (Box 105, Folder 28)
    - Letters to Mrs. Cruikshank, 1862-1865, Searle 686-689, 235058 (Box 105, Folder 29-32)